Four angels will come to destroy mankind.
Angels Fallen is a horror, fantasy, action film directed by Ali Zamani.
After the tragic loss of his wife battling the forces of darkness, Gabriel is persuaded to rejoin his former team of
demon hunters traveling from relatively obscurity in America to the deep unknown regions of Europe.
He is joined by his estranged best friend Michael who harbors a dark secret, the mystical
Hannah whose visions predict the future, and a motley crew of demon slayers.
After losing part of his team Gabriel must confront his tragic
past and decide who really is friend or foe.
Hannah, played by Nicola Posener.
Gabriel, played by Houston Rhines.
Michael, played by Michael Teh.
Lola, played by Li Jing.
Balthazar, played by Michael Madsen.
Ty, played by Said Legue.
Fallen Angels is a 1995 Hong Kong neo-noir crime comedy-drama
film written and directed by Wong Kar-wai.
It features two intertwined storylines—one tells the story of a hitman wishing to leave the criminal underworld (Leon Lai), the
eccentric woman he starts a relationship with (Karen Mok), and his agent (Michele Reis), who is infatuated with him.
The other story is of a mute ex-convict on the run from the police  (Takeshi Kaneshiro)
and a mentally unstable woman dumped by her boyfriend (Charlie Yeung).
Set in 1995 pre-Handover Hong Kong, Fallen Angels explores the characters' loneliness, their
alienation from the situations around them, and yearning for connections in a hectic city.
Wong initially wrote Fallen Angels as the third story of his preceding film, Chungking Express (1994), but split them into two
separate projects due to their cumulative length, and thus it acts not as a sequel but as a separate chapter.
Similar to Chungking Express, Fallen Angels features a fragmented
narrative that emphasises mood and atmosphere over structure.
Whereas its predecessor incorporates bright daytime colours, Fallen Angels consists of scenes
exclusively shot at night and using darker colours alongside bright neons.
Wong considered the two movies to be complementary
counterparts exploring contemporary Hong Kong.
Cinematographer Christopher Doyle extensively used wide-angle lens to distort the characters'
faces on the screen, conveying their isolation from the surrounding world.
Doyle also creates distorted tension in scenes of extreme
violence with frantic, out-of-focus visuals.
The soundtrack extensively uses trip hop and pop songs to convey mood and
maintain an "urban environment" that plays with popular culture.
Fallen Angels was released in September 1995.
Upon release, critics commented that its styles resembled those deployed in Chungking Express; many lamented that Wong
had become self-indulgent, though as time went on critics began to be more appreciative of the film.
At the 15th Hong Kong Film Awards in 1996, it won three awards: Best Supporting Actress
for Mok, Best Cinematography for Doyle, and Best Original Score for Roel A.
Garcia and Frankie Chan.
Retrospectively, critics commented that though Fallen Angels was not as groundbreaking as its
predecessor, it remained one of Wong's most captivating films, cementing his trademark styles.
The film's abstract, unconventional style, the context in which it was made, and its use of pastiche and intertextuality with regard to both popular
culture and its predecessor Chungking Express have led to the movie being described as a postmodern film and as suggesting a postmodern reading.
Since its release, Fallen Angels has been frequently cited as one of
Wong's best films and one of the greatest films of the 1990s.
The film has encompassed a large cult following, and is notable for being the last film Wong fully shot
in his native Hong Kong before embarking on more ambitious international productions.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.